Guide to the Harry C. Peterson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Harry C. Peterson papers
1879-1936
SC0107
Peterson, Harry C.
1.75 Linear feet
Includes administrative and personal correspondence, 1888-1936; reports, statistics, acquisition records, exhibit captions, and publications of the Stanford Museum, 1894-1917; and research materials compiled by Peterson on the Gold Spike (ceremonial spike used to connect the Union Pacific and Central Pacific Railroads), Stanford history, and Peter Coutts, including an original letter by Coutts, 1879. Peterson's major correspondent was David Hewes and there is some printed material on Hewes in the collection. Also includes copies of his newspaper column "The Story of Stanford University," 1919.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Peterson, born in Iowa in 1876, was curator of the Stanford Museum from 1900-1917; after leaving Stanford, he directed the Sutter's Fort Museum in Sacramento.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes administrative and personal correspondence, 1888-1936; reports, statistics, acquisition records, exhibit captions, and publications of the Stanford Museum, 1894-1917; glass slides of Stanford images probably used to illustrate talks; and research materials compiled by Peterson on the Gold Spike (ceremonial spike used to connect the Union Pacific and Central Pacific Railroads), Stanford history, and Peter Coutts, including an original letter by Coutts, 1879. Peterson's major correspondent was David Hewes and there is some printed material on Hewes in the collection. Also includes copies of his newspaper column "The Story of Stanford University," 1919.
Access Terms
Coutts, P. J. F. (Peter J. F.); Hewes, David.; Peterson, Harry C.; Stanford University. Museum of Art; Gold Spike.; Museums.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1888-1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1902-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1907-909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1918-1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1932-1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Museum: annual reports, 1902, 1910-17 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Museum: attendance statistics (1894-1917); other business papers (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Museum: daily account of acquisitions, May 1900-Feb. 1901 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Museum: guidebooks, rules for visitors, donor cards, and other publications (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Museum: articles and clippings about the Museum (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Museum: miscellaneous (notes for arrangement of exhibits, loan forms, notes on acquisitions) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Museum: gifts of David Hewes (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Museum: lace collection (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Museum: requisition forms, 1909-13 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Stanford Museum: early California history collection (captions) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Museum: Japanese collection (captions, etc.) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Museum: painting and fine arts collections (captions) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Museum: Egyptian collection (captions) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Museum: Stanford family collection (captions) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Museum: collections, miscellaneous (captions) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Museum: notes on arrangement of exhibits (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - David Hewes and the Gold Spike (notes taken by Peterson from Mr. Hewes’ account (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - David Hewes: printed material about (obituary, booklet on the David Hewes building, magazine articles) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - List of photographs, CPPR stereos and views of Stanford University [possibly photos taken or owned by H.C.P.] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mosaics, material about (collected by H.C.P.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Peter Coutts: research notes and original material about (includes April 4, 1879 Coutts original letter, signed) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Historical Association (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Museum: catalog lists (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “The Story of Stanford University,” copies from microfilm of Peterson’s newspaper column, bound volume (2 copies) (Box 3)
  - “The Story of Stanford University,” bound [original clippings?] (Box OS)